<Document>
  # Resomi

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobResomi" Scale="2" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  Resomi are a small avian species who have evolved over thousands of years to now resemble a humanoid like structure. Their wings have shrunk over time with shorter feathers, and gaining a set of fingers allowing them to manipulate and hold objects the same as any humanoid.
  
  The feathery plumes that grow from their crowns have been styled over the recent years to resemble the hair styles of other species.
  
  They have kept their feathery tails throughout their evolution. With bright and eccentric colors, they are one of the defining visual quality of a modern Resomi.

  ## Sounds
  The while Resomi have lost their beaks through their evolution, they still audibly resemble the sounds of a common bird. Their high pitched screeches slowly shifted to soft and pleasant chirps and squawks.

  ## Resomi Packs and Names
  Resomi culture is dominated by pack heirarchy structure, where Resomi will sort themselves into packs during their devloping years. These packs often include other Resomi from the same clutch or nursery with the pack acting as a family structure to support and guide Resomi during development.

  Resomi packs would often name themselves after their pack, and will be more trusting and caring to members of their pack from formation to their eventual death. However, it has been known that some Resomi reject other Resomi when forming a packs, instead choosing to cling to items, ornaments or weapons for support and comfort.

  While Resomi hatcheries has sought to maintain this culture, the Resomi's explansion into the across the stars have cause this historic culture to fade away. While some Resomi still chose to follow this structure, most forego it and go by other nicknames or names. With most names being named after colorful objects and food.

  ## Nightvision
  The Resomi have evolved to have light sensitive eyes which allows them to see in the dark. While most other species would require a flashlight or other light sourceto see in the dark,
  Resomi can visually see that same as if they were in a dimly lit room.
  However, headwear and glasses that with reflective coatings designed to protect the wearer from bright lights and flashes will block the Resomi's ability to see in the dark.

  Any glasses that would provide protection from flashes will block their nightvision ability.
  Using HUD variants allows you to keep your nightvision, at the cost of losing flash immunity.
  
  You can configure if you start with glasses or HUD in the loadouts for all relevant roles.
  
  ## Flash Vulnerability
  Their increased sensitivity to light comes at a cost, with Resomi being highly vulnerable to bright flashes. While a handheld flash would normally disrupt someone's vision for [color=#ffe100]5 seconds[/color], Resomi's sensitivity to light causes a regular flash to last [color=#ff6f00]10 seconds.[/color]
<Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingEyesGlassesSunglasses" Scale="4" Caption="Sunglasses block Nightvision"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingEyesHudCommand" Scale="4" Caption="HUDs will not block Nightvision"/>
</Box>
  ## HUD or Sunglasses
  Wearing a HUD Interface grants Resomi to see in the dark. While Sunglasses and Welding Masks will block this ability. Resomi can choose to switch between these types of head and eye wear to best suit their current situation. However... Resomi who use to use their innate Nightvision, can see themselves being ambushed well prepared foes.

  ## Damage Vulnerabilities
  Due to their smaller statue, Resomi are vulnerable to all forms of physical [color=#ffae00]brute damage[/color]. Taking [color=#ff6f00]15% more brute damge[/color] than a regular human.
The insulating nature of their feathers allow them to resist the cold, taking [color=#9ee5f7]10% less cold damage[/color]. While also being able to find comfort in cold and warmer climates.

  ## Claw attack
  The Resomi have evolved to have sharp claws on their hands, allowing their regular attacks dealing Slashing damage and inflicting minor bleeding. While their nimbleness allows them to attack a little faster than a regular human.

  ## Weapon Recoil/Knockback
  The smaller size of Resomi does have a big drawback, with increased recoil from large weapony. Shotguns, Rifles, Launchers and high caliber weaponry will inflict stamina damage and push the Resomi backwards. With the size of the weapon or caliber contributing to more stamina damage and knockback.
<Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="WeaponRifleLecter" Scale="3.5" Caption="Low recoil"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="WeaponShotgunKammerer" Scale="3.5" Caption="Medium recoil"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="WeaponLauncherRocket" Scale="3.5" Caption="High recoil"/>
</Box>
  Resomi will need to take intermittent breaks from combat when using these weapons, or they will be knocked prone from the repetetive stamina damage.
  
  Smaller caliber weapons like Pistols and SMGs will not inflict stamina damage, and will often be the choice of weapon for most Resomi.
  
  Resomi can mitigate the effects of weapon recoil by equipping and and activating Magboots or other forms of slip prevention.
</Document>
